ANTHONY RODEZ

720.418.9032 Louisville, CO Rodez.A@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Principal Engineer with deep and broad experience in small, medium, and large Fortune 500 companies, working directly with executives, teams, and projects across numerous business verticals. Solid track record of gathering requirements and translating them into scalable solutions with leading-edge technologies. Major strengths include interpersonal, quantitative, and problem solving skills.

- AWS Cloud / Data Engineering / Python
- Snowflake / Databricks / Data Warehousing
- AI-ML / Big Data / Data Science
- Software Engineering / DevOps /Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYTICS 2023-Present

AWS Senior Cloud Engineer (contractor)

Designing, developing, and deploying data solutions on AWS with tools such as: AWS Redshift, Quicksight, Starburst, Sagemaker, and Glue.

 Designing and maintaining data models, ETL, automation such as the AWS CDK and using Agile methodologies for a large AWS Redshift environment.

MedeAnalytics 2023-2023

Principal Data Engineer - Richardson, TX

Implemented a digital transformation from on-prem to AWS datalake using Iceberg tables, Trino, and PowerBI. Project managed the Transfer-in-Care analytics implementation - processing 12 TB of data for multiple providers.

Developed a process to upload and create Iceberg tables in AWS Glue notebooks.

Corellium 2022-2023

Principal Data Engineer - Delray Beach, FL

Developed company wide analytics for an IOS/Device startup using the latest in AWS, Python, Snowflake, Prefect, FiveTran, Segment, Google Analytics, Tableau and other best of breed technologies.

- Created Python ETL code to move large amounts of data into Snowflake.
- Developed a process for data sharing with partner companies.

Jupiter Intelligence 2021-2022

Sr. Software Engineer – San Mateo, CA / Boulder, CO

Developed a global climate platform for a series C \$54 million+ start-up at the intersection of data science, data engineering and software engineering. Leveraging the latest in AWS, Snowflake and data science to predict perils and climate change in Snowflake.

- Worked directly with software engineering, data science and product owners on delivering a GIS cloud platform.
- Developed a data warehouse for Geospatial data on Snowflake for petabytes of data.

Panasonic 2018–2021

Lead Data Scientist - Denver, CO

Led the data science effort on a \$100 million+ multi-year project on one of the largest V2X - connected vehicles projects across the US. Created models to add intelligence to the Cirrus platform. Leveraged the latest technologies in AWS such as Kinesis Analytics, Machine Learning, Athena, Glue, Lambda, QuickSight, Redshift, Snowflake, and Tableau.

- Developed multiple data science models such as Logistic Regression, Linear Regression, and SMOTE models.
- Wrote python code for data pipelines, web scraping, and modeling for GIS, segmentation, telematics data.

Data Analytics 2012–2018

Principal Consultant - Denver, CO

Led and delivered entire data analytic environments from end to end - leading ETL requirements, data modeling, implementation, and project management on small to large projects. Conducted business analysis, logical and physical database design, database optimization, load strategy design, implement security and change management.

- London Trust Media (Technology) Developed a multi-million dollar Amazon S3 Data Lake with server less technologies using Athena for schema on read, and QuickSight for visualization. Developed customized data pipeline with Python, Lambda, Cloud Watch and EC2 for automated reporting, working directly with the US and Brazil teams.
- Coalfire (Security)— Implemented best in class cloud data warehouse from end-to-end using AWS cloud services, Informatica Cloud for data pipelines, Tableau for visualization, and Python for log files.

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthonyrodez/

ANTHONY RODEZ

2 | P a g e

■ **Zimmer Biomet (Healthcare)** – Data Integration project for \$13.4 Billion merger of Zimmer Biomet, one of the largest Biomedical companies in the Spine division using SAP and SAP Data Services for ETL. Worked with global teams.

- Pinnacle (Agriculture) Developed an SSIS XML based regulatory system that saving money and reduced auditing.
- Kaiser Permanente (Healthcare) Led the Business Objects 4.1 implementation in the Colorado region for a reporting system valued at over \$50M dollars. The implementation included a large node clustered environment of 20 servers that provided fail over and load balancing support for 1200+ Deski and 1800+ Webi reports with 400+ users and 100s of bursed reports. The ETL was run on Informatica to load 1 Terabyte of data into a data store from DB2, Teradata, Oracle and SQL server.
- Comcast/NBC-NETO (Technology/Media)- Developed Big Data/predictive analytic reporting using Pentaho ETL and Cognos 10.2 and SSAS cubes saving Comcast support over \$5M monthly due to reduction of truck roles and proper use of LOQs (Line of Questioning) in an SCRUM/Agile team environment. The data was sourced from large-scale IVR systems using Pentaho ETL.

Qlearvista 2008-2012

Senior Consultant – Denver, CO

Managed initiatives along with the executive team on progress and implementation methodology on multi-million dollar projects. Designed data warehouses using Kimball and Immon methodology as well as customized reports using best practices.

- Agrium Implemented Sales dashboards and data warehouse internationally in BO XI3.1 for Sales, Finance, Operations, and IT.
- CoBank (Banking) Developed and migrated over 200 reports in Cognos 8.4 in an Inmon Data warehouse for a banking entity.
- Vail Resorts (Resort) Developed a Kimball data warehouse with SSIS and SQL Server 2008 for the Marketing and Sales.
- WJ Bradley (Banking) Implemented the Microsoft BI Stack using MS SQL Server suite of tools for a startup mortgage firm.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud: Snowflake, AWS, GCP, AZURE, Databricks, Starburst, Trino Iceberg, AWS LakeFormation

Data Science: Apache Spark, Azure Machine Learning, Jupyter Notebooks, RStudio, AWS ML

Python Libraries: Beautiful Soup, PETL, Matplotlib, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Seaborn, Scikit Learn, Tensorflow

Programming: SQL, Python, R programming, JAVA, C, C#, PowerShell, PySpark

BI Tools: SAP - SAP BW, Business Objects, Webi & Deski, Designer, Excelsius, BO Explorer, Lumira,

Crystal Reports, BO Mobile / **IBM** - Cognos 10.2 Report Studio, Query Studio, Framework manager, Transformer, Powerplay, Analysis Studio, Event studio, DMR, Brio Query / Sisense /

Microsoft - SSRS, SSMS, SSAS, SSIS / Oracle - Discoverer / Virtualization - Denodo

Visualization: Kepler, Tableau, Apache Superset, PowerBI

ETL Tools: Prefect, Informatica – Cloud & Power Center 8.6, SAP Data Services, MS SSIS, Pentaho, Prefect **Databases:** AWS Redshift, DynamoDB, BigQuery, Oracle, SQL Server, Postgres, Teradata, DB2, MS Access

ERP Systems: SAP, Oracle, PeopleSoft, J.D. Edwards, IBM systems, Netsuite–OpenAir

Web: Dreamweaver, Fireworks, Dynamic HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Wordpress, Flask PM Tools: Atlassian - JIRA, Confluence, Trello, Rally, MS Project, Agile / SCRUM, SmartSheets

Documentation Tools: Lucidchart, Miro, MS Visio

APIs: REST, WSDL, HTTP, Postman, Python Requests Infrastructure as Code: Terraform, AWS CDK, AWS CloudFormation

Containers: Docker, AWS ECR

Version Control: Azure DevOps, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Subversion

EDUCATION

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) - Professional Certificate in AI & ML 2021-2024

Focus: Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence

University of Colorado Denver - M.B.A. Information Systems 2003

Focus: Programming, Web Design, Databases, Systems Architecture

University of Colorado Denver - M.S. Finance 2003

Focus: Security Analysis, Economics, Statistics

University of Colorado Boulder - B.A. International Business 1999

Focus: Biology, Pre-Med, Business, Languages

LANGUAGES

German - Germany - Level: B2 / Spanish - Spain - Level: C1 / French - Alliance Française Denver, CO - Level: A1

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Applied Data Science Program: Leveraging AI for Effective Decision Making – MIT – March 2024

Certified Scrum Master (CSM) – Scrum Alliance – Oct 2023

Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer – Python Institute – Jan 2021

Apache Spark Course – Databricks San Francisco, CA June 2016

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthonyrodez/